Little girl?
I'm a policeman.
Little girl!
Don't be afraid, okay?
Little girl?
TEAM STAYIN' ALIVE
What's the difference
between men and women?
- This a joke?
- No. Serious.
Never met a woman
who knew how to turn off a light.
They're born thinking
the switch only goes one way... on.
They're struck blind
the second when they leave a room.
Every woman I ever have let a key,
swear to God,
I come home, house's all lit up.
My job, apparently, because...
because my chromosomes are different,
is I have got to walk through that house
and turn off every single light
this chick left on.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, baby.
Reverend Shane's preachin' to ya,
now, boy.
Then, the same chick minds you,
she'll bitch about global warming.
There's one Reverend Shane wants
to quote from the Guy Gospel saying,
"Darlin', maybe you and every other
pair of boobs on this planet
"just figured out
that the light switch goes both ways,
"maybe we wouldn't have
so much global warming."
- You say that?
- The polite version.
Still, man.
That earns me this look of loathing
you would not believe.
And that's when
the Exorcist voice pops out,
"You sound just like
my damn father!"
"Always yelling about the power bill,
telling me 'turn off the damn light!'"
- What do you say to that?
- What I want to say is,
"Bitch, you mean to tell me
you been hearing this your entire life
"and you are still too damn stupid
to learn how to turn off a switch?"
I don't actually say that, thought.
That would be bad.
- I go with the polite version.
- Very wise.
How's it with Lori, man?
She's good at turning off lights.
Really good.
- I'm the one who sometimes forgets.
- Not what I meant.
- We didn't have a great night.
- Look, man. I may have...
failed to amuse with my sermon,
but I did try.
Less you could do is speak.
That's what she always says.
"Speak. Speak."
You'd think I was the closed-mouth
son of a bitch ever to hear her tell it.
Do you express your thoughts?
Do you share your feelings?
That kind of stuff?
Thing is...
Lately, whenever I try,
everything I say makes her impatient.
Like she didn't wanna hear it after all.
It's like she's pissed at me
all the time and I don't know why.
That's just shit couples go through.
It's a phase.
The last thing she said
this morning,
"Sometimes, I wonder
if you even care about us at all."
She said that in front of our kid.
Imagine going to school
with that in your head.
The difference
between men and women?
I would never say
something that cruel to her.
Certainly not in front of Carl.
All available units,
high speed pursuit in progress,
Linden County
requests local assistance.
Highway 18 eastbound, GTA, ADW,
2-17, 2-4-3.
Advise extreme caution.
Suspects are two males Caucasian.
Be advise.
One Linden County officer is wounded.
Dispatch unit 1, unit 3,
we are 10-97 and code 100,
Highway 18, EB of interstate,
please advise.
Sounds like they chase all these idiots
up and down every back road we got.
Maybe we'll get on one of them video
shows? What do you think?
Leon, stay focused, keep a round
in the chamber and your safety off.
Would be kinda cool.
Get on one of them shows.
Holy shit!
- Gun! Gun!
- Put it down!
Put the gun down!
Rick?
I'm all right.
I saw you get tagged.
That scared the hell out of me.
Me too.
That son of a bitch shot me.
You believe that?
- It catch you in your vest?
- Yeah.
Shane, you do not tell Lori
that happened. Ever.
You understand?
He's hit!
Leon, get that ambulance down here
and tell him
there's an officer's down!
You look at me,
you stay with me, you hear me?
Stay with me.
Hey, buddy.
We still here. We still hanging in.
I'm sorry, man. I say the same crap
every time I come in here.
Everybody pitching all these.
They want me to bring 'em down.
They hope you come back real soon.
Linda and Diane from dispatch
picked these out.
I can tell.
I'm just gonna set these
on your side table, okay?
That vase. That's something special.
Fess up. You steal it
from your grandma Jean's house.
Hope you left her
that spoon collection.
Shane?
Shane? You in the john?
Nurse, help!
Nurse! Help!
Lori?
Carl?
Is this real? Am I here?
Wake... wake up.
- Daddy! Daddy!
- Carl...
Carl, I found you.
Daddy, I got this sumbitch.
I'm gonna smack him dead.
- He say something? I though he did.
- He called me Carl.
You know they don't talk.
Mister? What's that bandage for?
- What?
- What kind of wound?
You answer me, damn you!
What's your wound?
Tell me or I will kill you.
Got that bandage changed now.
Was pretty rank.
What was it? The wound?
Gunshot.
What else? Anything?
Gunshot ain't enough?
Look, I ask and you answer.
It's common courtesy, right?
Did you get bit?
- Bit?
- Bit. Chewed.
Maybe scratched.
Anything like that.
No, I got shot.
Just shot. As far as I know.
Just let me.
He's cold enough.
Fever would have killed you by now.
- I don't think I have one.
- Be hard to miss.
Take a moment.
Look how sharp it is.
Try anything.
I will kill you with this.
Don't you think I won't.
Come on out when you're able.
This place.
Fred and Cindy Drake's.
Never met them.
I've been here. This is their place.
It was empty when we got here.
Don't do that.
They'll see the light.
There's more of them
out there than usual.
I never should have
fire that gun today.
Sound draws them.
Now they're all over the street.
Stupid. Using the gun.
But all happened so fast.
I didn't think.
You shot that man today.
- Man?
- Weren't no man.
What was that out of your mouth?
It wasn't a man.
You shot him.
In the street. Out front. A man.
Friend, you need glasses.
It was a walker.
Come on.
Sit down. Before you fall down.
Here.
Blessing.
Father we thank Thee
for this food, Thy blessings.
We ask you to watch over us
in this crazy days. Amen.
Mister, you know what's going on?
I woke up today.
In a hospital.
Came home. That's all I know.
- But you know about the dead people?
- Yeah, I saw a lot of that.
Out on the loading docks.
Piled in trucks.
No, not the one they put down.
The ones they didn't, the walkers.
Like the one I shot today.
'Cause he'd ripped into you.
Try to eat you,
take some flesh, at least.
If this is the first
you're hearing it,
I know how it must sound.
They're out there now,
in the street?
They get more active
after dark sometimes.
Maybe it's the cool air or maybe
it's just me firing that gun today.
But we'll be fine
as long as we stay quiet.
Probably wandered off by morning.
Listen.
One thing I do know,
don't you get bit.
I saw your bandages,
that's what we were afraid of.
Bites kills you.
The fever burns you out.
But then after a while...
You come back.
I've seen it happen.
Carl.
Your son?
You said his name today.
He's a little younger than your boy.
He's with his mom?
I hope so.
Did you ask him?
You gunned shot.
We got a little bet going.
My boy say you're a bank robber.
That's me. Deadly as Dillinger.
Ka-pow.
Sheriff's deputy.
It's okay. Dad is here.
It's nothing.
One of them must have bumped a car.
- You sure?
- Happened once before.
Went off a few minutes.
Get the light, Duane.
The blue one on the street.
Same one as last time.
I think we're okay.
That noise.
Won't it bring more of them?
Nothing we can do about it now.
Just have to wait it out
till morning.
She's here.
Don't look.
Get away from the windows.
I said go. Come on.
Quiet.
Come on. Quiet.
It's okay. Cry into the pillow.
Do you remember?
She...
She died in the other room.
On that bed.
And I... couldn't do about it.
That fever, man.
Her skin gave off heat
like a furnace.
I should have put her down.
I know that.
You know what?
I just didn't have it in me.
She's the mother of my child.
Are we sure they're dead?
I have to ask. Least, one more time.
They're dead.
Except for something in the brain.
That's why it's gotta be the head.
You all right?
Need a moment.
They're alive. My wife and son.
At least they were when the left.
How can you know?
- By the look of this place.
- I found empty drawers in the bedroom.
They packed a few clothes.
Enough to travel.
Anybody could have broken in here
and stole clothes.
See the framed photos on the walls?
Neither do I. Some random thief
take those too, you think?
My photo albums, family pictures.
All gone.
Photo albums.
My wife... same thing.
There I am packing survival gears.
She's grabbing photo al...
They're in Atlanta, I bet.
That's right.
- Why there?
- Refugee center.
A huge one, they said.
Before the broadcasts stopped.
Military protection. Food. Shelter.
They told people to go there.
Said it'd be the safest.
Plus they got that disease place.
Center for Disease Control.
Said they were working out
how to solve this thing.
Gas line been down
for maybe a month.
Station got his own propane system.
Pilon's still on.
That feels good, right?
Duane, dressing room back there.
What do you say, Duane?
Thank you.
Atlanta sounds like a good deal.
Safer, anyway. People.
That's where we were heading.
Things got crazy.
You can't believe the panic.
Streets weren't fit to be on.
Then my...
My wife couldn't travel.
Not with her hurt.
Had to find a place and lay low.
And after she died.
We just stayed hunkered down.
I guess we just froze in place.
Plan to move on?
Haven't work up to it yet.
A lot of it's gone missing.
Daddy, can I learn to shoot?
I'm old enough.
You'll learn. But we'll do it carefully.
Teach you to respect the weapon.
That's right. It's not a toy. You pull
the trigger, you have to mean it.
Always remember that, Duane.
Here.
Load up.
Take that one. Nothing fancy.
Scope's accurate.
Conserve your ammo.
Goes faster than you think.
Especially at target practice.
Take this for the car.
- You sure you won't come along?
- A few more days.
By then, Duane will know how to shoot
and I won't be so rusty.
You got one battery.
I'll turn mine on
a few minutes of every day at dawn.
You get up there,
that's how you find me.
- You think ahead.
- Can't afford not to.
- Not anymore.
- One more thing.
They may not seem like much,
one at a time.
But in a group?
All riled up and hungry?
- There you watch your ass.
- You too.
You're a good man, Rick.
I hope you find your wife and son.
Be seeing you, Duane.
Take care of your old man.
Leon Basset.
Didn't think much of him.
Careless and dumb.
But I can't leave him like this.
You know they'll hear the shot.
- Let's not be here when they show up.
- Let's go, son. Come on.
You read your comic books a while.
I'll be upstairs.
- Daddy?
- It's all right, Duane.
You stay there, son.
Don't you come up here.
Jenny.
Come on, baby.
I'm sorry this happened to you.
Come on! Come on!
Broadcasting on emergency channel.
Will be approaching Atlanta
on Highway 85.
If anybody reads, please respond.
Hello. Hello.
Can anybody hear my voice?
Anybody out there?
Anybody here? Please respond.
Can you hear my voice?
Hello, can anybody hear my voice?
- ... can you hear my voice?
- Yes, I can hear you. Over.
If anybody reads, please respond.
Broadcasting on emergency channel.
Approaching Atlanta on Highway 85.
If anybody reads, please respond.
We're just outside the city.
- I couldn't warm him.
- Try and raise him again.
Come on, son.
You know best how to work this thing.
Hello, hello. Is the person
who called still on the air?
This is officer Shane Walsh
broadcasting to unknown person.
Please respond.
He's gone.
There are others. It's not just us.
We knew there would be.
That's why we have the scanner on.
Lot of good it's doing.
I've been saying for a week
we have to put signs out on 85.
Warn people away from the city.
Folks got no idea
what they're getting into.
Haven't had time.
I think we need to make time.
That's a luxury we can't afford.
We are surviving here,
we are day to day.
- Who would you proposed we send?
- I'll go. Give me a vehicle.
Nobody goes anywhere alone.
You know that.
Officer.
Go and take a sit, buddy.
You all right. Come on.
Wait, you're pissed at me?
Be pissed at me all you want,
it's not gonna change anything.
I'm not putting you in danger.
I'm not doing it for anything.
If I make you feel like sometimes
you want to slap me upside the head...
Tell you what, you feel that need,
you go right ahead. I'm right here.
You cannot walk off like that
all half-cocked.
If you're not doing it for my sake
nor for your sake, fine. But just...
You do it for him.
That boy's been through too much.
He won't lose his mother too, okay?
I'm a good mom.
You tell me you okay.
Wasn't that hard.
Mom?
What's up, buddy?
She's in there. Go on.
I don't want you to worry.
Your mom is not going anywhere.
Go finish your chores.
Hello?
Police officer out here!
Can I borrow some gas?
Anybody home?
Easy, now. Easy.
Not gonna hurt you.
Nothing like that.
More like a proposal.
Atlanta is just down the road a ways.
It's safe there.
Food, shelter, people.
Other horses too, I bet.
How's that sound?
Here we go. Good boy.
Now come with me? Come.
Let's go easy, okay?
I haven't done this for years.
No... Easy, boy!
Let's go.
Steady. There's just a few.
Nothing we can't outrun.
Lori, Carl. I'm sorry.
Hey you.
Dumbass.
Hey, you in the tank.
You cozy in there?